LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
Angels and demons were circling over me,
Crossing a brambly path of stars and milky ways.
He who does not perceive his calling,
does not know true happiness.
Watch in awe! Watch in awe!
Flying in glory, Flying in glory
I am calling, calling now. Spirits rise and falling.
To be with you longer
Calling, calling...
in the depth of longing
To stay myself longer
The flow may swallow you, flying in glory
POLICE
Laughing Man...
Laughing
Man
Case
Special
Investigation
HQ
This one too...
What's going on?
Yamaguchi.
Chief... Nibu.
What are you doing here so late?
What a rude fellow.
I was working.
Were you still working too?
Yes.
How about we go for a drink?
Why don't you join me once in a while?
Um, wha...
I'm done for today.
THE
VISUAL
DEVICE
LAUGHS
Yes?
Oh, this is Yamaguchi;
I worked with you at the central office.
Do you remember?
Yamaguchi?
Oh, how have you been?
It's been quite a while.
Sorry to suddenly call so late,
but there's something I want to talk to you about.
Can we meet now?
Now?
I don't mind.
Did something happen?
Do you remember the Laughing Man case?
Laughing Man...?
Oh...
the one where someone kidnapped the presidents of micro-machine manufacturers and asked for ransom.
"Corporate terrorism" so to speak, that happened six years ago right?
I'm on the special investigation team for that case now...
But there has been some suspicious activity within.
The police are fighting over their jurisdiction?
No, it's going on at a higher level.
Please, I want to meet with you and talk about this.
I'll be there in about an hour.
Okay, I'll be waiting.
Thanks.
So there was an interceptor in my eye too!
What, did Togusa stay up all night?
Yeah.
He said he had been waiting for someone since last night.
What's in that box?
This? It's Batou's work-out equipment.
He bought another one?
I don't know what part of himself a cyborg like him trains with those.
You've got that right.
Doesn't he have something else to spend his money on?
Oh, you woke up?
On the capitol highway at night...
Police officer burnt black?
Are you absolutely certain...
that the call you received was from the officer who died in that accident last night?
Yes.
He wanted to talk with me about some suspicious activity in the uppers levels of the central office.
Do you think his death is related to that?
I have no proof, but the timing is just too perfect.
What were the results of the investigation?
An unexpected accident caused by sight interference.
So it's possible that it was just an accident.
But...
Let him finish his story.
Even if it was just an accident,
If your former colleague did get a hold of something, we need to confirm that.
I'll give you three days, find something by then.
Thank you very much.
The Laughing Man case, eh...?
What do you think?
I had forgotten about that until now.
I see that the Special Investigation HQ hasn't been broken up yet.
If you consider the number of companies that received a threat,
it's the biggest case of corporate terrorism that has happened since the war.
The central office can't easily back out of the case because of public opinion.
But they seem to be taking their time on it.
It seems that in the upper levels they still have split views on who the culprit is.
One theory says that
radicals who oppose foreign
corporations that advance
cyberbrain and cyborg technology
A conspiracy that has arisen from the races between corporations...
Blackmail solely for money, or many other theories.
Lau
Laughing
Laughing Man
They don't even have any idea of the culprit's nationality, sex, age,
or even if it's done by one person or multiple people.
But there's one theory that many agree on;
that the culprit is a special class-A hacker.
Only the first few cases were the work of a special A-class hacker.
I believe the rest were pretty ordinary.
To be honest,
I just don't like that case, the culprit's profile included.
But if the central office's high officials are trying to pull something,
don't you think that we should do something?
Mr. Togusa?
Nice to meet you.
I'm Yamaguchi's wife.
I'm sorry for your loss.
But how do you know about me?
I heard about you from my husband.
Actually, I want to give this to you, Mr. Togusa.
It came from my husband this morning.
There was a letter inside,
and it told me to give this to you.
To me?
I will take a look.
Are you sure that these are it?
Yes...
I think so.
Next.
22 to 56.
35 to 28.
Next.
What are these?
What did Yamaguchi want me to see?
Mine does something like that sometimes.
Oh yeah, I need to call home.
It's me.
I don't think I'll be able to come home today either.
Yeah.
Yeah, I see.
Just be sure that you lock up and be safe.
Yeah, I'll do my best.
Good night.
Now then, I guess I'll wash my face and look at them again.
Is two days going to be enough time for me?
Wait...
C97, 35 to 28.
It's not there...
Get C98.
Just as I thought.
Get C96.
This too.
C92.
4 to 13.
42 to 30.
This too.
There's no camera in any of these pictures.
So...
What does an elite member of Public Safety Section 9 want from me?
You didn't come to Yamaguchi's funeral, did you?
I thought I would see you there.
I was busy with my job.
Did you see his wife?
Yeah.
What an idiot.
He left such a beautiful young wife behind.
It seems that the Special Investigation section is having lots of trouble.
Oh, you're talking about the Laughing Man case?
Everyone's working on it without sleeping.
Do you have any leads on the case?
This is starting to sound like an interrogation.
If you're not allowed to talk about it, that's okay.
I don't mind.
It seems that you'd be able to look up info on it even if I kept quiet here.
We found a primary suspect.
Weren't there a hundred of those?
This one's different.
I'm sure of it.
He has a grudge against Serrano too.
Serrano Genomics.
The micro-machine maker that was targeted in the first Laughing Man case.
Are you close to arresting that suspect?
No, the brass is being indecisive.
But this time we have the circumstantial evidence we need.
All we need to do now is to get a hold of a clincher.
How?
Using an interceptor.
An interceptor?
Is that the visual device
that was introduced after the
visual interception law was
revised three months ago?
Yeah.
If we can set one up in the suspect, we can get something.
Since we won't need to tail him for three months.
If he goes to a medical facility, we can have one set up in him.
If it works, he won't have any privacy.
We can even check out the parabola that his piss makes.
What did you just say?
The parabola his piss makes?
That's it.
I see, an interceptor.
Yes, I found out that all the pictures that Yamaguchi had
Were taken from the point of view of the Special Investigation team on the Laughing Man case.
So that was the high officials suspicious activity?
Yes.
But interceptors themselves aren't illegal,
and if you submit the proper documents any police-related personnel are allowed to use them.
But I could not confirm that any documents were submitted.
The presence of a third party, which is required under the law, was not confirmed either.
According to Fukami,
the Special Investigation team was
looking for a chance to set up
an interceptor in the suspect.
But judging from the prefectural police's records,
I believe the interceptors were set up inside the eyes of the Special Investigation team
during the health examination at the station.
That seems a bit too much to observe their work attitude.
Aren't the interceptors supplied by Serrano Genomics?
The police have officially used the incident victim's product.
I smell something fishy.
And Fukami, who is keeping an eye on Serrano's president, has an interceptor in his eye.
The Serrano people and other officers do not know that.
It seems that they don't get along well when they're "friends".
So the pieces are starting to come together.
Wait...
Doesn't that mean that what Togusa did was all seen by someone?
Yes, I would like to take immediate action, but we don't have enough evidence to do this head-on.
Shall I shake them up a little?
Sorry, but we're not open yet.
Who is it?
It's me.
Oh, it's you. Don't scare me like that.
You're still cowardly. Your cyborg body must be crying.
Did you come here just to say that?
No way.
I want to give this scoop to one of the reporters that visit your bar.
You can probably guess that I don't want this going to any government affiliated media...
Unfortunately I don't get that kind of customer.
Is that so?
Then I'll report that this is a tip-off from you,
and that this place is a server for information terrorism to the cyber police.
It seems that you still like to tell jokes that wake me up.
I'm happy that you understand.
I'll give you the money in cash as usual.
Thank you.
I'm counting on you.
You're going home?
Why don't you have a drink?
Do you have any alcohol that isn't watered down?
That's harsh.
Mr. Nibu!
Is it true that the interceptor that was introduced after the law was revised
is being used unlawfully within the police department?
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about the rumour that the Special Investigation team members have interceptors in their eyes.
Who said that?!
Just answer my question please.
I don't know anything!
I'm going to have you arrested if you keep this up!
Mr. Nibu, my camera!
Shut up.
You're not driving your car to work?
Shut up!
Mr. Nibu!
Chief Nibu ran away after taking the reporter's camera
Suspicion that
the visual device
is being used
illegally...
It seems that stubborn Aramaki is behind all of this.
We have already taken measures.
Yes, it can't be helped.
But, we can get out of this by paying the equivalent of a captain's retirement.
Thank you.
My wife has said that she isn't satisfied with the real estate in Holland.
Yes, really.
We will hold the press conference here tomorrow.
The incident that was brought up in certain newspapers
about the unlawful use of visual devices in the Niihama Prefecture Police Department's Special Investigation team...
The superintendent general himself is going to have a press conference?
This caused more reaction than I expected.
He was the chief of the prefectural police when the Laughing Man case occurred.
Looks like there's something going on inside the police network that they want to hide.
We will now begin the press conference.
Due to suspicion that interceptors were being used unlawfully,
in violation of the visual interception law,
which was raised the other day in weekly magazines and such,
we conducted an internal investigation, and
District Chief Nibu Kunihiko has given a statement that he was responsible for this.
We believe that the chief officer was stuck on the Laughing Man case,
so he implanted interceptors into each investigator's cyberbrain to gather information.
He admitted that he temporarily lost his ability to make the right choice because of the stress...
and he is deeply sorry for committing such an act.
But we must admit that the chief officer's actions deviated from his job.
As of today, the chief officer will be given a disciplinary dismissal,
and we apologise deeply to the investigators who were working on this case, and their families.
What about the responsibility of the more senior officials?
I believe there will be an announcement from the General.
There's a rumour that the senior officials and Serrano are working together.
We understand that the selection of the product was done within the limits of the law,
and I have heard that our adoption of the product was done through official bidding.
You didn't answer my question!
Aren't you all the ones who requested the revision in the visual interception law?
Superintendent general, it seems that you are going to move to Holland after you retire,
isn't that where Serrano's parent company is?
Is there any relation there?
I have no obligation to answer such a personal question!
What do you mean you have no obligation?
Oh my.
Hey, isn't the camera moving weirdly?
You haven't changed, Superintendent-general Daidoh.
Nice to meet you. You know who I am, right?
That's...
What's going on?
What's wrong, Takegawa?
Mr. Daidoh, I was thinking that I shouldn't get involved in your world anymore.
When I deal with that garbage dump of a world, it really makes me sick.
That's why I didn't say anything during your foolish acts.
I knew everything.
In other words, I grew tired of this uselessness.
How unfortunate.
Hey, you were watching right?
That chief officer's cyber brain...
But today's act was just horrible. Too horrible.
It was foolish, but it wasn't funny.
That's why I, unwillingly, have to challenge you all again.
Three days from now, you're going to have a reunion with the graduates of your farce troupe, right?
Please tell the truth there.
If you pull a fake act again,
I will have to erase you from this stage.
Takegawa!
Get an ambulance! Get an ambulance!
The conference continues, but we will return to the studio.
Mr. Sakurai at the conference hall...
Is it the real guy?
Major, confirm the situation right away.
Roger.
She's so cold and human
It's something humans do
She stays so cold in her soul, she's so number 9
She's incredible math
Just incredible math
And is she really human?
She says there's something new
But wake a lithium flowe, just about to bloom
I smell lithium now
Smelling lithium now
How... is she what she doesn't say
She doesn't say
How is she when she doesn't suffer
I wonder what she does when she wakes up
When she wakes up